

Can KILIÇ

METU Software Engineer Frontend Developer

July 27, 1998

🔁 Ankara, Turkey

+905530649089

canklc9598@gmail.com

Languages

English

Turkish

Russian



Hard Skills

- ReactJS | Redux
- JavaScript | TypeScript
- HTML / HTML5
- CSS/CSS3 (SASS/SCSS/LESS)
- Bootstrap | Ant-Design
- NodeJS/Express | Postman
- MongoDB/Mongoose | Firebase
- Python

Memberships



@cnkilic



@can-kilicc-

Soft Skills

- **Self-motivated;** independent, organized, and proactive.
- Eager to learn and open to new ideas
- Adapting different environments, responsibilities and people.

About Me

After my graduation in Civil Engineering at METU, I have **gathered my courage to make the switch to software.** I dedicated all my free time to full-stack courses. After acquiring basic knowledge about the industry, I have moved on to specialize in Front-End development using the **ReactJS library**.

Currently, I am employed as a **Front-End developer** at Inavitas, where we bring data analysis to life through visually **appealing and user-friendly tables and graphs using ReactJS**. In my free time, I stay current with industry advancements by **doing side projects and learning new technologies**.

I am eager for a challenging opportunity that allows me to utilize my skills and experience while offering opportunities for growth and advancement.

Certifications

- React The Complete Guide (50 hours) includes Props, States, Custom Hooks, React Router, Redux, Next.js, TypeScript and RESTful APIs – Udemy
- Full-Stack Web Development Bootcamp 2022 (55 hours) with HTML, CSS (Sass, Less, Bootstrap), JavaScript, Nodejs and MongoDB and Github Udemy
- Data Structures and Algorithms (20 hours) with Big O, Arrays, Hash Tables, Linked Lists, Stacks, Queues, Trees, Graphs, Recursion, Sorting, Searching, Dynamic Programming – Udemy
- Using Python to Access Web Data || Python Data Structures || Getting Started with Python – Coursera

Experiences

Inavitas | Front-End Developer

September 2022 - Ongoing

- Built functional, Reusable, Unit Testable, Easy to read and debug user interfaces by using React.js (HighCharts.js, AGGrid), JavaScript and CSS (Ant Design).
- Worked with scrum and agile development principles using JIRA and collaborated with team members using Microsoft Teams.
- Gained experience on REST APIs, Micro-service architecture, Asynchronous programming (Axios), Git, GitLab, ESlint and Figma.

Arina Digital | Front-End Developer

April 2022 - September 2022

- Build pixel-perfect, user friendly web and mobile interfaces by using HTML5, CSS3 (Sass, Less, Bootstrap), JavaScript, jQuery, Swiper Slider, Gulp.js etc...
- Developed the whole front-end of **Teknik Card** and participated in the renovation and development stages of projects such as Mbis and Klimasan.
- Experienced in responsive UX/UI development and became familiar with xDesign and Figma design tools.

Education

BC Civil engineering METU Sept 2016 - Aug 2021

• CGPA: **3.60/4.0** (5th/456)

Activities

Work and Travel

June 2019 - Sept 2019 Washington DC, USA

 Learned how to communicate with people with a different language and express myself in English better.